# JÜRGEN BRANDSTETTER (PHD)

Founding Engineer / Product Manager / CTO

@ j@brandstetter.io

**Q** Linz, Austria, EU

## **SUMMARY**

With more than 10 years of experience as a founding engineer, I'm accustomed to wearing many hats. I manage and develop the product's underlying software architecture and its UX by working closely with the customer. Communication skills are a cornerstone of my role, enabling me to effectively translate complex technical concepts between cross-functional teams and customers/C-Level/Board. When it comes to the technical team, I oversee the development process, write code reviews, draft job offers, conduct interviews, provide constructive performance reviews, and mentor them to become seniors in their roles. Most importantly, I don't shy away from uncomfortable or complex conversations, employing an empathetic approach.

# **EXPERIENCE**

## Founding Engineer / Co-Founder (CTO)

#### amy.app

Personal Al Maths Tutor

My job is to lead the development of our Al-driven maths tutor.

## Visiting Researcher

#### Microsoft Research (Fuse Lab HRI/HCI)

**=** 06/2014 - 10/2014

Manhattan, NYC, USA

Microsoft's Research Arm

I worked on persuasive robotic technology. The goal was to motivate coworkers to stand or walk at least once an hour.

# Android and Web Developer

## **OpenResearch**

**=** 07/2012 - 02/2013

Vienna, Austria, EU

App Development Agency

Software Architect and Developer. Android, HTML5 Developer

## Android Developer

#### **OpenResearch**

iii 09/2010 - 02/2011 ♀ Vienna, Austria, EU

App Development Agency

- Cluster Algorithms for Map-Markers
- ÖAMTC-Android App

## Co-Founder and Founding Engineer

#### **WFRistIN**

Online company register similar to the yellow pages but on Maps

Project Management, UI-Designer, Customer Support, Salesman, Dynamic Webpage Developer (GWT)

# Product Manager

## A-K-D Wohnservice GmbH

Interior Design and Production

· I created the companies intern enterprise system, based on AJAX/PHP/MySQL

## **SKILLS**

**Team** 

Team Lead **Project Management** 

**People Development** 

Tech

**Typescript** React Node.js **Postgres** OpenAI-API **Firebase** Cloud-Functions Material UI Next.js

## **EDUCATION**

## PhD, Human Interface Technology

University of Oxford (UK), University of Canterbury (NZ)

**=** 01/2013 - 12/2016

## M.Sc., Media Informatics

Vienna Institute of Technology (AT), University of Copenhagen (DK)

**=** 01/2011 - 12/2012

## B.Sc., Computer Science

**Technische Universität Wien** 

**#** 01/2007 - 12/2011

# Engineer, Electronic and Computer Science

## **HTBLA-Steyr**

**=** 01/2001 - 12/2006

### **LANGUAGES**

<b>English</b> Native	•••••
<b>German</b> Native	•••••
<b>Arabic</b> Beginner	••••